FIKRI NURSYAWALI

CHEMICAL ANALYST

Bandung City, Indonesia +62 85161672812 fikrinursyawali28@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a chemical analyst graduate from one of the best chemical vocational high schools in Indonesia, having experience as a raw material quality control analyst for 2 years and 6 months in one of the 2nd largest pharmaceutical companies in Indonesia. I also have experience in one of the largest health companies in Southeast Asia in the nutritional division from 2021 until now with a position as a chemical laboratory Analytical Center staff, I have also been placed as a front office staff to receive and prepare samples from customers before being distributed to sublabs certain parameters according to the parameters requested by the customer, preparing reports on analysis results and issuing them to be sent to customers, monitoring laboratory conditions and accommodation in accordance with ISO/IEC 17025, managing the flow of reagents and laboratory equipment in and out, coordinating with suppliers for equipment repairs and communicate with other departments related to laboratory operations. In addition, I have expertise in operating instruments such as AAS, HPLC, GC, ICP-OES, UV-Vis Spectrophotometer, IR Spectrophotometer, Kahl Fischer Autotitator, Dissolution tester, pH Meter, Refractometer, Viscosity tester and several other tools. I have a disciplined attitude, agile and thorough, have high ambition towards achievement and targets and have a high curiosity about new things.

PROFESSIONAL SKILL

Good Laboratory Practice
Good Document Practice
Personel Hygiene
Good Manufacturing Practice
Standard Managemen ISO/IEC 17025

TECHNICAL SKILL

Proximate Analysis
Atomatic Absorption Spectrophotometry
High Perfomance Liquid Chromatography
ICP-OES
Gas Chromathography
UV-Vis, IR & Fluoro Spectrophotometry
Dissolution Tester

WORK EXPERIENCE

Analytical Center Staff/ Analyst Chemical

Jan 2023 - Now

Sanghiang Perkasa Kalbe Nutritionals, PT/ Karawang, Indonesia

- receipt and checking of samples that have been distributed by laboratory sample delivery officers using the oracle system
- Analysis of raw materials, finished products, and trial products using the proximate method with routine parameters Protein, Fat, water, ash, carbohydrates, and dietary fiber.
- input analysis results into the oracle system
- Perform proficiency tests according to laboratory capacity
- Developing analysis methode
- due diligence and inter-analyst accuracy

WORK EXPERIENCE

Analytical Center Front Office Staff/ Administrator Laboratory

Sanghiang Perkasa Kalbe Nutritionals, PT/ Karawang, Indonesia

Sept 2021 - Dec 2022

- Receive and prepare samples from customers
- Distribution sample to internal Sub Laboratory or external Laboratory
- Preparing reports on analysis results and issuing them to be sent to customers
- monitoring laboratory conditions and accommodation in accordance with ISO/IEC 17025
- · managing the flow of reagents and laboratory equipment in and out,
- · coordinating with suppliers for equipment repairs
- · communicate with other departments related to laboratory operations

Analytical Center Staff/ Analyst Instrument

June 2021 - Aug 2021

Sanghiang Perkasa Kalbe Nutritionals, PT/ Karawang, Indonesia

- receipt and checking of samples that have been distributed by laboratory sample delivery officers using the oracle system
- Analysis of raw materials, finished products, and trial products using the instrument method with routine parameters Assay, B Complex Vitamin, Fat, Mineral, Heavy Metals.
- input analysis results into the oracle system
- Perform proficiency tests according to laboratory capacity
- · Developing analysis methode
- due diligence and inter-analyst accuracy

Quality Control Dept. Staff/ Raw Materials Analyst

Dec 2018 - June 2021

Sanbe Farma, PT/ Bandung, Indonesia

- Analysis of raw materials using the in house & USP method with routine parameters Assay,
 Vitamin, Fat, Mineral, Heavy Metals, water content, ash, and other in house specification
- Make a report of analysis result
- Maintenance instrument tolls
- Calibration and verivication analytical balance & pH meter
- Transfer methode with R&D Analyst to develope existing method

Analyst & Laborant/Intern

July 2017 - Sept 2017

Laboratory of ruminant livestock nutrition and animal feed chemistry, Faculty of Animal Husbandry, Padjadjaran University

- Analyze animal feed using the proximate method
- Assist and supervise student practice

EDUCATION

Vocational High School/ Vocational Degree, Chemical Analyst

2015 - 2018

SMKN 7 Bandung (Chemistry High School)

graduated on time with very good exam results (A) with a score of 81 out of 100